A Finding Aid to the Holly Solomon Gallery Records, circa 1948-2003, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hollsolg
Archives of American Art
- Holly Solomon Personal Papers, circa 1948-2002; Series 12; (Boxes 170-182, 194; 13.1 linear feet)
  - Wedding Photograph, 1953 (Box 194)
  - Oversized Christmas Card, 1992 (Box 194)
  - Matted Exhibtion Annoucement signed by Holly, 1992 (Box 194)
  - "What's Cooking" Lecture Poster, 1998 (Box 194)
- Sound, Video, and Film Recordings, circa 1966-2001; Series 13; (Boxes 183-190; 7.6 linear feet)
  This series is comprised of recordings collected by the Holly Solomon Gallery. The content of the recordings are both about the gallery itself, and the artists it represented. The series is organized into artworks created by gallery artists, performances recorded live at the gallery, and the publicity Holly Solomon, the gallery and its artists received. The recordings range from before the gallery's opening in 1975 until after its closure in 2002, with most recordings coming out of the 80s and 90s. The work of video artist Nam June Paik is highly represented within the series through some of his actual video artworks, as well as through numerous documentaries and television interviews with him. Prominent artists William Wegman and Laurie Anderson are both represented through original artworks and publicity. Exhibition annoucements and gallery installation instructions accompany some of Anderson's sound cassettes used in her gallery shows. Also included are six empty cassette cases of hers with poems on the covers. Many of the publicity videos are of Holly Solomon herself, being interviewed for television and documentaries as early as 1989 for an episode of Art Market Report all the way up until just before her death in 2002 when she was profiled in a docuemntary about women art dealers called Off the Canvas. Recordings are on 164 videocassettes (136 VHS, 21 U-matic, 7 Betamax), 13 sound cassettes, 2 sound tape reels, and 1 sound disc.
  Sound, video, and film recordings are arranged in rough alphabetical order by artist. Where there was no artist name listed, the title was used if present.
  - Artworks by Name June Paik (Box 183)
    - "American Flag" on American Parade TV Show, 1984; (3 videocassettes: 2 VHS, 1 U-matic) (Box 183)
      ("Design consultant" on credits.)
    - Baroque Painting, 1988; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 183)
      (Label reads "Electronic Arts Intermix.")
    - Bye Bye Kipling, 1986; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 183)
      (Label reads "Nam June Paik 1986.")
    - "Chase tape NJP,", 1992; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 183)
    - Concerto Grosso Opus #6, 1988; (2 videocassettes: 1 VHS, 1 U-matic) (Box 183)
    - The Colours of Music, 1995; (2 sound cassettes, envelope, letter, postcard) (Box 183)
      (Artwork composed for BBC Radio 3. The letter thanks Paik for his contribution to the radio series, and that his part appears in progamme 2.)
    - Frog with Betsy Connors, 1990; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 183)
    - "Icons,", circa 1980-1989; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 183)
    - "Inside Heart Paris", circa 1986; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 183)
    - Living with the Living Theatre, 1989; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 183)
    - "Robot Channel,", circa 1986; (3 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 183)
      (Two labels also read "heart channel for robot.")
    - Topless Cellist with Charlotte Moorman, 1995 April 29; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 183)
    - Tribute to John Cage, 1976; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 184)
      (One label reads "Cage "3x"", and one label reads "Electronic Arts Intermix.")
    - Wrap Around the World with David Bowie, 1988; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 184)
  - Artworks by Various Artists (Box 184)
    - Anderson, Laurie, 1978-1981 (Box 184)
      (Cassette labels read "Handphone table," "Telephone, 1981" and "Artist," the five blank cassette case covers are of typed out poems with dreams being the subject and a label that reads, "Laurie Anderson 4 '80" in handwriting. There is an exhibition announcement and gallery set-up instructions for the exhibition titles "Quartets For Four Listeners" and for "Telephone.")
    - Anderson, Laurie, Sharkey's Day and O Superman, 1985 May 6; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 184)
    - Bark, Jared, Slotin's Light from Lights: on/off, and excerpts from Krishna Concerete, 1974 and 1976; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 184)
    - Barry, Robert, Otherwise, 1981; (1 sound disc: vinyl, oversized item house in box 194) (Box 184)
    - Blue Cowboys, Tower Green, circa 1996; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 184)
      (Label reads Erika Wilson, Steve Fontaine.)
    - Bobi Bird Song, 1987; (1 sound cassette) (Box 184)
      (Label reads "Bobi Avis Theo, produced by Kazuko Oshima and recorded at Secret Sound WK Studio, New York.")
    - Compilation of Performance Artist's Videos, circa 1990; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 184)
      (A few of the artists featured on the video include Laurie Anderson, David Byrne, and William Wegman.)
    - Downing, Glenn, Compilation tape, circa 1994; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 184)
      (Label lists eight different titles spanning from 1991-1994)
    - Downing, Glenn, I am Ragged but I'm Right, 1993; (2 videocassette: VHS) (Box 184)
      (Label reads "Compilation" of seven pieces from 1986-1993)
    - Fab Five Freddy, Director's Reel, 1988; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 184)
      (Label lists three music videos from the groups Statsasonic, Boogie Down Productions, and E.P.M.D.)
    - Fairey, Shepard and Ryan Lesser, Attention Deficiency Disorder, 1995; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 184)
      (Label reads "an alternate graphics production, Giant, produced at AVX, Providence, RI")
    - Gabbiano, circa 1980-1989; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 184)
      (One label reads "master")
    - Girouard, Tina, Pinwheel, 1977 March 1; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 185)
      (Tape broken)
    - Gordon, Jeff Artsounds Collection, 1985; (1 sound cassette) (Box 185)
      (Label lists artists: Bob Gruen, Tom Wesselmann, Thomas Schmidt, The Tubes, Philip Johnson, Larry Rivers, Connie Beckley, Italo Scanga, Klaus Nomi, Yura Adams, and Jon Borofsky)
    - Heske, Marianne, Mountains of the Mind, 1986; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Hutchinson, Peter, Alphabet, 1995 November 12; (3 videocassette: 2 U-matic, 1 VHS) (Box 185)
    - Hutchinson, Peter, Avocado, 1975; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 185)
    - Hutchinson, Peter, End of Letters, 1981; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 185)
      (Label reads orginal recording is from 1971)
    - Kirchoff, Silvia and Andreas Troger, Strom (Current), 1992; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Marti, Virgil, Couch, 2000 May 1; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
      (Label reads "Ardmore Train Station May 1, 2000 8 a.m." and has an address label from a Carol Cole)
    - Matta-Clark, Gordon Film Excerpts, 1990, December 3; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
      (Label reads "Transferred from 3/4' master at Electronic Arts Intermic")
    - Meijer, Marie, Art Ache, circa 1990; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
      (Label reads "Part 1, English Subtitles")
    - Operation Stars and Stripes Forever, circa 1990-1999; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
      (Label reads "Allen/Martin Productions")
    - Oppenheim, Dennis, Recall- Take I, 1989 November 29; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Pretty Little Princess Culture Institute, People Pleasers, circa 1990-1999; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Rist, Pipilotti, (Entalstungen) Pipilottis Fehler, 1988; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Rist, Pipilotti, Blutclip, 1993; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Rogers, Dick, Cadmium Yellow, circa 1982; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 185)
    - Rosi, Gianfranco, Boatman, 1994; (3 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 185)
      (Two handwritten labels, one commercial)
    - Turner, Darryl and Hilton Als, Silent Twins, 1990; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 186)
      (Label reads "Camera News Inc/ 3rd World Sponsoring Org / Newsreel")
    - Van Tiegham, David, Ear to the Ground, Siberia, and excerpts from two Marymount tapes, circa 1982; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 186)
    - Waplington, Nick, TX: Nothing, 1999; (3 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 186)
      (Label reads "UK version.")
    - Warhol, Andy, Selections from the Andy Warhol Videotape Collection(circa 1960-1969,), circa 1990-1999; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 186)
      (Label reads "The Andy Warhol Foundation for the Visual Arts")
    - Wegman, William, Selected Video Works 1970-1978 and Dog Baseball 1986, 1994; (6 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 186)
      (Various commercial and handwritten labels)
    - Wegman, William, Selected Works: Reel 7 and Anthology, 1977-1978; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 186)
      (Label reads "Electronic Arts Intermix")
    - Wegman, William, Sesame Street Segments, 1998 October; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 186)
    - Wegman, William, The Best of Wegman 1970-1978, 1981; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 186)
    - Wegman, William, The Hardly Boys in Hardly Gold, 1995; (6 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 186)
    - Wooster, Ann-Sargent, No Means No, 1993; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 186)
    - Wynne, Rob, Sleepwalking, 1996; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 186)
  - Live Gallery Recordings (Box 187)
    - Jimenz, Elisa, "Spring Show,", circa 1996-1999; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "shot by Aaron.")
    - Kushner, Robert, The Persian Line, Part 2, 1976 March 4; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads, "recorded at The Holly Solomon Gallery.")
    - Litt, Larry, Video -Mudang, Shamanism/Shamanisn't, Homage to Nam June Paik, 1992 November 7; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "at Holly Solomon Gallery.")
    - Litt, Larry, Video-Mudang, 1993 May 24; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "with Won Qi Sol and San Won Park, Holly Solomon Gallery")
    - "LuLu LoLo and Thomas Lanigan-Schmidt, Installation at Holly Solomon Gallery,", 1995 October 10; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 187)
    - "Paik at Holly Solomon,", 1993 May 6; (1 videocassette: U-matic) (Box 187)
      (Label has the business card of Andreas Troeger taped to it.)
    - Patkin, Izhar, The Meta Bride, 1983 Aprl 3; (2 videocassettes: 1 VHS, 1 Betamax) (Box 187)
    - "Silver Apples at Holly Solomon Gallery,", 1996 October 18; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "Soho Mojo, video by Jackie Clark.")
    - Untitled live music recording, circa 1990-1999; (1 sound cassette) (Box 187)
  - Nam June Paik Publicity Videos (Box 187)
    - ART/new york, Nam June Paik, Prisoner of the Catohde Ray, 2000; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "no. 53" of the ART/new york series.)
    - El Ojo del Soho, circa 1990-1999; (2 videocassetes: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "Arturo Carvajal" who is the host of the Argentine-based art television program.)
    - The Electronic Super Highway, Nam June Paik in the 90s, 1995; (2 videocassetes: VHS) (Box 187)
      (This portrait of Nam June Paik was produced as a "video catalogue" for the national touring exhibition The Electronic Super Highway.)
    - High -Tech Allergy, Nam June Paik, 1995; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads produced by the "Kunstmuseum Wolfsburg" this piece documents Nam June Paik's installation works of the mid-1990s.)
    - New Years Eve Broadcast with Tiger Lives, 1999 December 31; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 187)
      (A PBS broadcast of Paik's art direction of Seoul's New Years celebration.)
    - NJP Images, circa 1970-1999; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Videotape contains promotional images of Paik.)
    - Play It Again, Nam, Un portrait du Nam June Paik by Jean-Paul Fargier, 1990; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 187)
      (Label reads "Ex Nihlo, Canal +, Centre Pompidou and electronic Arts Intermix.")
    - Various news reports on the work on Nam June Paik, 1967-2000; (16 videocassettes: 2 U-matic, 14 VHS) (Box 188)
      (Various news reports and profiles from the national networks like CBS, NBC and CNN, and foreign networks like the BBC, KBS (Korean Broadcasting System), SBS (Seoul Broadcasting System). Also included is footage of Paik meeting President Bill Clinton in 1998.)
  - Artist and Gallery Publicity (Box 188)
    - Art Documentaries, 1983-2002; (8 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 188)
      (Labels read "ART/new york, Video as Art," "ARTSEEN, William A. Rabinovitch," "ART today, Vol. II No. 2," "Andy Warhol: The Complete Picture," "John Cage: I Have Nothing to Say and I am Saying It," "Originals in Art, Richard Serra," "Pattern and Decoration: The Great Untold Story.")
    - City Arts, circa 1997; (4 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 188)
      (Three labels read "Dealers Choice, episode 315" and one label reads "For the First Time, episode 410.")
    - First Artist Portfolio, 1986; (2 videocassetes: VHS) (Box 188)
      (Label reads "Vermillion Editions Limited.")
    - Frost, Phil, circa 1990-1999; (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 189)
    - Garrin, Paul, circa 1990-1999; (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Video produced for German television and features his collaboration with Nam June Paik.)
    - Jimenez, Elisa, 1996-1999; (4 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Labels read "The New York Women's Collections Spring 1999," "Videofashion Monthly, The Fashion Beat volume 21 number 8" and an untitled video interviewing Solomon and Jimenez at the Gramercy Park Hotel.)
    - Laningan, Thomas, Eric Sanko, and Pat Olesko, 1997; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Label redas produced by "The Lower Manahattan Cultural Center" also includes "Holly Solomon Gallery Tour.")
    - Lemaire, Agathe, 1986 May 6; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Label reads "Les Enfants D'Alice.")
    - Mengbo, Feng, 1989; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Label reads "Chinese Television Network.")
    - Mook, Cho Sung, circa 1990-1999; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Label reads "Messenger.")
    - New clips and Interviews with Holly Solomon, 1989-2001; (11 videocassettes: 10 VHS, 1 sound cassette) (Box 189)
      (Included is Solomon being interviewed for; NPR's All Things Considered, Art Market Report, ART/new york, Christie's Auction House, two Japanese language TV shows about fashion and food, and a UNICEF charity event at Sotheby's.)
    - Off the Canvas, 2001-2002; (5 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Four videos of separate interviews with Solomon at home and at Chelsea Gallery for the documentary, and one video of the documentary's trailer.)
    - Rosenblatt, Adolph, 1987 December 18; (1 videocassete: VHS) (Box 189)
      (Label reads "The Wisconsin Magazine, Coffee and Art to Go.")
    - Wegman, William, circa 1982-1989; (4 videocassettes: 2 VHS, 2 Betamax) (Box 189)
      (Various William Wegman TV appearences including his 1982 guest spot on David Letterman.)
    - Zucker, Joe and Judy Pfaff, circa 1982; (6 videocassettes: 4 Betamax, 2 U-matic) (Box 190)
      (Three labels read "Artscene excerpt interview.")
  - Miscellaneous Sound and Video Recordings (Box 190)
    - Answering machine microcassette tapes from the Holly Solomon Gallery, circa 1990-1999; (2 sound microcassettes) (Box 190)
      (One tape is of the gallery's recorded greeting, the other of a message from Nam June Paik.)
    - "The Boy Witch,", circa 1968; (1 sound tape reel, two enevlopes with return letter from Ogilvy and Mather Inc. Advertising) (Box 190)
    - Child's sound recording of pop music, circa 1966; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 190)
    - Cinemagique electronic press kit, 2001 December 5; (1 videocasette: VHS) (Box 190)
    - Unidentified exhibition footage, circa 1990-1999; (1 videocasette: VHS, PAL format) (Box 190)
  - Sound Recording, Otherwise by Robert Barry, 1981; (1 sound disc from box 184) (Box 194)
- Electronic Records, circa 1980s-1990s; Series 14; (Box 190; 0.4 linear feet)
  - Electronic Records, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 190)